Terri Hammons

<u>terri@terrihammons.com</u> | 512-484-4092 http://terri-hammons-portfolio.herokuapp.com

Experienced knowledge professional with a strong background in research, information services, and process development and documentation. Additional skills and education in web development, providing a unique ability to merge library and information strategies with technical execution.

EDUCATION

Certificate in Web Development, Full Stack Flex, The Coding Bootcamp at University of Texas (July 2017)

Master of Library and Information Science, University of Texas at Austin

Bachelor of Arts in Sociology, University of Texas at Austin

KEY STRENGTHS

Outstanding research and information management capabilities combined with intensive technical skill development

History of success in both leadership and individual contributor roles with progressively increasing responsibilities

Proven ability to explain complex research strategies and business processes to stakeholders at all levels

Sharp, quick learner; willing and able to develop and own end-to-end workflows

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Web development: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Node.js, Express, MySQL, MongoDB; Python (beginner level); MS Office + OneNote; Google Mail & Apps; Confluence, JIVE social platforms; SharePoint (calendars, workflows)

EXPERIENCE

PRODUCER

Healthcare Education Associates (A Division of Wilmington FRA), Remote/Austin, TX • 2016

Extensive Research, Writing, and Content Development in support of end-to-end production cycle for conferences on targeted healthcare topics

- Distilled detailed technical information from research interviews and industry publications into structured conference agendas and event descriptions
- Successfully produced conferences on a variety of new topics, such as diabetes and population health, and risk adjustment data validation audits
- Composed copy for sales and marketing collateral, including conference webpages, brochures, email blasts, and telesales scripts.
 Program examples at http://www.frallc.com/pdf/H421.pdf
 and http://www.frallc.com/pdf/H351.pdf

MANAGER—LIBRARY SERVICES, FACT CHECK RESEARCH & COPYRIGHT PERMISSIONS

Pearson, Austin, TX/Remote • 2006-2016

Team Leader and Manager, Accountable for the Processes and Resources to deliver fact checking, copyright permissions, and information services for educational assessment programs

- Successfully coordinated and prioritized fact checking and acquisition of copyright permissions for 25+ assessment projects, employing collaborative work methods to meet aggressive deadlines
- Supported all aspects of the fact checking and copyright permissions processes, from gathering project requirements and crafting project dossiers, to providing first-line troubleshooting for the rights management database that was implemented to replace a manual tracking system
- Following mergers and new business acquisitions, identified efficiency measures to incorporate new projects into team workflow without having to add resources
- Represented assessment division in the design and implementation of the company's global knowledge repository
- Developed a question-and-answer reference service for the assessment division, and created a knowledge sharing website on the company's Jive platform

FREELANCE/CONTRACT WORK

Permissions Consultant—2016-present, **QUAD Graphics**

Apply strong skills and knowledge in copyright permissions and text sourcing to "deep dive" audits of textbooks in order to identify and evaluate third-party content.

Project deliverables include a methodical page-by-page review of each book, analysis of permissions status for all copyrighted content, and population of detailed permissions logs.

Section Violinist—2000-present, Corpus Christi Symphony Orchestra, Laredo Philharmonic

Orchestra

Orchestra musician for award-winning, regional orchestras in south/central Texas. Performances with renowned soloists, including Itzhak Perlman, Joshua Bell, Van Cliburn, Andre Watts, Evelyn Glennie, and Edgar Meyer, and with bands such as Break of Reality, Wilson Phillips, the Texas Tenors, and more.

- Created a permissions audit process to ensure compliance with client contract requirements and copyright law
- "Super searcher" for the team—tracked hard-to-find rights holders using biographical sources, public records, library databases, and other online sources
- Developed training materials on finding and evaluating information sources, and led training efforts for internal content development staff, outside vendors, and independent contractors
- Series of promotions to positions of increasing responsibility, including to Team Lead in 2007 and Senior Research Librarian in 2010.
 Subsequently promoted to team manager in 2010
- Editorial Services Employee of the Year; identified as "brave, creative, strategic and smart"

REFERENCE/TEXAS DOCUMENTS LIBRARIAN

Texas State Library and Archives Commission, Austin, TX • 2002-2006

Deliver Reference and Research Assistance to a Diverse Customer Base, including state employees, legislators, students, and members of the general public

- As part of a public-facing Reference team, key player in helping to meet the agency's legislatively mandated 95% customer satisfaction rate
- Collaborated with other Reference Team members to respond to approximately 600 written and telephone requests per month. Patron requests covered wide variety of topics, including legislative history research, genealogical research, and queries on state government agencies
- Assisted in developing and maintaining the Reference Department's electronic library of written responses to frequently asked questions
- Created and updated procedures documentation for the management of the Texas government documents collection
- Selected for Employee of the Quarter award, and identified by colleagues as "highly resourceful" and a "master multitasker"

RESEARCH SPECIALIST

TManage, Austin, TX • 1999-2001

Create Company Knowledge and Information Resource Center, and provide information and knowledge management services

- Developed and managed the services provided through the company Information Resource Center (IRC), including market research, competitive intelligence, and dissemination of information to company executives and staff
- Published a bi-weekly summary of current news items relevant to the company. Worked on special projects such as finding information for company bylined articles, and producing fact sheets used in sales efforts
- Created market and industry fact sheets used by company executives for regional and national events and conference presentations.
- Coordinated primary research efforts, including focus group studies and surveys